

tking3612@gmail.com | 678-332-4542 | Woodstock, GA 30188

Summary

Regularly leads helpers and instructs less experienced professionals in basic and advanced techniques. A professional with an outstanding background in applying a strong work ethic to perform daily construction duties. Successful Creator bringing seven years of expertise in building construction, maintenance, and remodeling to a new position with a challenging and rewarding employer. A committed job seeker with a history of meeting company needs with consistent and organized practices. User-minded Web Developer prioritizes usability and adaptability during projects. Designs sites and apps to attract users with aesthetically pleasing interfaces and exceptional UX elements. Ambitious, career-focused job seeker, anxious to obtain an entry-level Software Engineer position to help launch career while achieving company goals. Adaptable Software Engineer ready to support operations from conception through post-release support. Skilled creator of efficient code and exciting user experiences. Eager to elevate ongoing development projects or create novel software solutions geared towards driving increased usership. Offering progressive experience in owning web-based projects from concept and design through testing, implementation, and client updates.

Skills

- Highly motivated employee with a desire to take on new challenges.
- Strong worth ethic, adaptability, and exceptional interpersonal skills.
- Diligent in producing exceptionally clean, strong, and secure code.
- Successful at achieving browser, device, and operating system compatibility objectives while satisfying client desires and producing robust, sophisticated designs.
- Comfortable working within large-scale collaborations or on individually developed assets.

- Skilled in working under pressure and adapting to new situations and challenges to best enhance the organizational brand.
- Hardworking and reliable Software Engineer with strong ability in software development.
- Highly organized, proactive, and punctual with a team-oriented mentality.
- Adept at working effectively unsupervised and quickly mastering new skills.
- Intelligent in planning tasks by performing simple and complex calculations.

Experience

Woodland Steelworks **Carpenter** 07/2020 - Present

- Manufacture household furniture and outdoor furniture.
- Manufacture large furniture projects.
- Operate CNC machine for production.
- Design new products and improve production methods.
- Organize and manage materials for production.
- Punctual Carpenter with extensive knowledge of wood quality and composition.
- Collaborates successfully with homeowners in selecting building materials.
- Strictly adheres to building plans to promote customer satisfaction and return business.
- Provides high-quality carpentry through precise and detail-oriented approaches.
- Driven to exceed customer expectations while meeting all budget and schedule requirements.

Builder King Carpenter

06/2018 - 06/2020

Chappell Construction Group Carpenter

01/2015 - 06/2018

- Responsibilities included installing flooring, installing cabinetry, installing tile, managing project designs and materials, property management, and overseeing remodels.
- Safety-minded in following procedures, maintaining organized workspaces, and using tools properly.
- Displayed keen attention to detail and design.
- Recognizes customer service as a valuable tool to deliver overall quality and satisfaction.
- Committed to fulfilling all customer expectations through careful adherence to design plans and requests.
- Responsibilities included labor work, trim carpentry, heavy machinery, cleaning job sites, and demolition.
- Knowledgeable and skilled in various construction techniques, procedures, carpentry tools, and equipment.
- Team-oriented in communicating with others to complete excellent rough carpentry work and share information needed to complete finish carpentry tasks.
- Versatile Carpenter with 7 years of experience on various construction sites, including several new home developments.
- Completes tasks on time and with little guidance.
- · Successful at guaranteeing client satisfaction through meticulous and longlasting work.
- Efficient Carpenter equipped with tools necessary to complete tasks on time and with little guidance.

Education and Training

General Assembly **Software Engineer** January 2023

Woodstock High School High School Diploma May 2013

Website, Portfolios, and Profiles

- Website/Portfolio: https://dash.generalassemb.ly/Taylor King/build-your-own-personal-website
- LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/taylor-king-se